Elliot Connors is a formerly depressed writer from the Rust Belt, a formerly depressed region that, much like Elliot, has enjoyed something of a renaissance in recent years. His prose has been honored or featured in the Best American Essays of 2021, the Adroit Journal, the Yale Literary Magazine, McSweeney's Internet Tendency, and the Yale Record, the world's oldest humor publication, of which he was Editor in Chief. At Yale, he studied under Susan Choi, Anne Fadiman, and Mark Oppenheimer. In 2019, he received a Richter Fellowship to live in rural Québec and research the curse a priest put on his family that caused 5 of his relatives to commit suicide. He is currently working on a memoir about that experience, as well as developing several television pilots and assisting an acclaimed screenwriter with his wide-ranging portfolio. Beyond writing, Elliot works as a Senior Data Analyst for the homepage of the New York Times, and previously conducted research on decarceration for the Vera Institute of Justice.

Selected Stage and Screenwriting

Mark and the Metaverse	Animated Half-Hour Comedy	2023
Bethesda Friends and Lovers	Live-Action Hour Mystery Comedy	2023
Whose Life	Live-Action Half-Hour Comedy	2022
In Lieu of Flowers	Live-Action Half-Hour Comedy	2021
How I Met Your Mother	Live-Action Half-Hour Spec	2021
Mark and the Metaverse	Stage Play	2022
McDonald's, Milkman, Stallions	Stage Sketches	2020
Selected Prose		
Prone "Notable Essay" in the Best American Essays of 2021, Adroit Prize Finalist		2021
A Curse and a Blessing: Unearthing My Family's History of Suicide in Québec Richter Fellowship		2021
Just for Teens Issue, Letter from the Editor The Yale Record		2019
In Memoriam/Fuck 'Til You Drop Issue, Letter from the Editor The Yale Record		2019
Flat Earth Issue, Letter from the Editor The Yale Record		2019
Sponsored Issue, Letter from the Editor The Yale Record		2019
The Thirteen Raddest Things About Turning 13! McSweeney's Internet Tendency		2017
W/ 1 F		

Work Experience

Bays Thomas Productions | Executive Assistant | New York, NY

Aug. 2022 – Present

2022

As the executive assistant to an acclaimed screenwriter, I oversee all administrative aspects of his life and contribute to his wide-ranging portfolio of projects across television, film, and digital media.

The New York Times | Senior Data Analyst | New York, NY

Oct. 2021 – Present

Alongside product managers and newsroom editors, I drive engagement strategy on the New York Times's homepage. I won the 2022 Publisher's Award for my work launching an international version of our homepage.

Vera Institute of Justice | Research Analyst | Brooklyn, NY

Jun. 2020 – Aug. 2021

Alongside doctorates, lawyers, and advocates, I researched bail, parole, and sentencing reform efforts in New York State. Coauthored the first <u>paper</u> to examine the impact of bail reform and COVID-19 on New York jails.

Education

Yale University | B.A. English Literature, Computer Science certificate, cum laude (3.87) May 2020 Honors: Distinction in the major; Richter Fellowship for senior thesis research; published in Yale Lit Magazine Activities: Editor in Chief of the Yale Record, Co-President of the Yale Undergraduate Jazz Collective, First-Year Outdoor Orientation Leader, Tutor for Integrated Immigration and Refugee Services, Fifth Humor Sketch Comedy

Skills: Python, R, SQL, Git, GCP, AWS, dbt, Java, C, Excel, InDesign

Language: French